{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The Redfield ratio is an index of concentration of", "opta": "carbon, hydrogen and oxygen", "optb": "nitrogen, potassium and iron", "optc": "carbon, nitrogen and phosphorous", "optd": "carbon, phosphorous and sulfur", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Removal of solids is generally considered as a", "opta": "Primary treatment", "optb": "Secondary treatment", "optc": "Tertiary treatment", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All of the following species are considered coliforms except", "opta": "Enterobacter aerogenes", "optb": "Klebsiella pneumoniae", "optc": "Salmonella typhi", "optd": "Escherichia coli", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sulfur pearl of Namibia, Thiomargarita namibiensis", "opta": "is the worlds largest bacterium", "optb": "stores high concentrations of nitrate in a huge internal vacuole which takes up 98% of the organisms volume", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "is the worlds smallest bacterium", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chemical precipitation of phosphorus is", "opta": "primary treatment", "optb": "secondary treatment", "optc": "tertiary treatment", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "Ultramicrobacteria or nanobacteria are the dominant bacteria in marine systems", "optb": "Ultramicrobacteria or nanobacteria are so numerous that they are a major food source for heterotrophic flagellates", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Coliforms are used as indicator organisms because", "opta": "they are present wherever enteric pathogens are present", "optb": "a testing procedure with great specificity is easy to perform", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hyphomycete fungi", "opta": "produce nonmotile tetaradiate conidia", "optb": "grow in leaves and the infected leaves are the preferred food source for some aquatic insects", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Loss of carbon through the microbial loop in oligotrophic environments is __________ to/than the loss of carbon through the microbial loop in copiotrophic environments.", "opta": "greater", "optb": "lesser", "optc": "approximately equal", "optd": "half", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Metabolism of dissolved organic material released by phytoplankton allows heterotrophic bacteria to become part of the particulate organic matter that is passed up the food web to be metabolized and released as mineral elements and CO2 at each transfer. This sentence describes the", "opta": "microbial loop", "optb": "Winogradsky column", "optc": "Redfield ratio", "optd": "Gibbs free energy", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "All members of Hyphomycetes are also members of Fungi, but not all members of Fungi are members of Hyphomycetes", "optb": "All members of Fungi are also members of Hyphomycetes, but not all members of Hyphomycetes are members of Fungi", "optc": "All members of Hyphomycetes are members of Fungi, and all members of Fungi are members of Hyphomycetes", "optd": "No member of Hyphomycetes is a member of Fungi", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The amount of oxygen dissolved in hypolimnion water in the winter is __________ to/than the amount of oxygen dissolved in hypolimnion water in the summer", "opta": "greater", "optb": "lesser", "optc": "approximately equal to", "optd": "half", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Members of all of the following genera of bacteria typically are found in a maturing Winogradsky column except", "opta": "Clostridium", "optb": "Rhodospirillum", "optc": "Chlorobium", "optd": "Escherichia", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Because it can be used with a variety of media and allow a resuscitation step the __________ technique has become the common and often preferred method of evaluating the microbiological characteristics of water.", "opta": "most probable number", "optb": "Winogradsky", "optc": "MUG", "optd": "membrane filtration", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "A Winogradsky column is used to filter out microorganisms from a water sample taken from a deep black smoker", "optb": "A Winogradsky column is used to demonstrate interactions and gradients that occur in aquatic environments", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "A Winogradsky column is used to filter out microorganisms from non-aquatic environments", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Trickling filter comes under", "opta": "primary treatment", "optb": "secondary treatment", "optc": "tertiary treatment", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following species in water reveal the presence of fecal pollution of human or animal origin?", "opta": "E.coli", "optb": "Fecal Streptococci", "optc": "Clostridium perfringens", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Activated sludge undergoes", "opta": "Primary treatment", "optb": "Secondary treatment", "optc": "Tertiary treatment", "optd": "any of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rate of flux of oxygen in air is __________ to/than the rate of flux of oxygen in water.", "opta": "greater", "optb": "lesser", "optc": "approximately equal", "optd": "half", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ is an environment like __________ where microorganisms are functioning in an extremely thin film of water and where oxygen-containing air is close to them.", "opta": "low oxygen diffusion environment; soils", "optb": "high oxygen diffusion environment; soils", "optc": "low oxygen diffusion environment; lakes", "optd": "high oxygen diffusion environment; lakes", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}